Hamza Hawkins

Software Engineer Intern at Microsoft

Summary

Hi,

I have been programming since I was 10 years old. I started by learning about scripting languages and as I aged, I jumped into more demanding projects. I initially gained experience in programming robots and programming video games, then I ventured into programming back end services, websites, and mobile apps. I am currently attending University of the District of Columbia to attain my bachelors degree. With my experience, passion, and determination, I've been blessed with the opportunity to intern at Microsoft for 4 summers in a row. Being someone who's passionate in software engineering, I'm always looking for opportunities to further apply what I know to solve more challenging problems and to learn more.

Feel free to send me an email or a message to get in contact with me.

- Hamza Hawkins

Experience

Software Engineer Intern at Microsoft

May 2017 - Present

CEO/Lead Engineer at Snikwah Interactive Studio

May 2015 - Present

Designed, developed, and published mobile apps, mobile games, and websites

Lead Software Engineer at BRAQS

December 2016 - May 2017 (6 months)

- Developed various mobile projects in NodeJS
- Gained Experience in leading a team of software engineers on projects

Teacher at STEM exCEL

September 2016 - December 2016 (4 months)

• Taught middle school students programming and game development

Software Engineer Intern at Microsoft

May 2016 - August 2016 (4 months)

- Worked on the Azure Functions team
- Developed extensions for Azure Functions in Visual Studio Code

• Assisted in development with the CLI for Azure Functions

Software Engineer Intern at Microsoft

May 2015 - August 2015 (4 months)

- Worked on the SQL Azure Performance team
- Developed features in C# for a diagnostic tool in troubleshooting performance problems
- Developed features in C++ and C# for SQL Azure in the SQL Engine and frontend
- Acquired an understanding in working as a software engineer on a large scale

Explorer Intern at Microsoft

May 2014 - August 2014 (4 months)

- Worked on the SQL Azure Connectivity and Availability team
- Developed a diagnostics tool for assisting engineers in investigating login failures
- Worked as a software developer engineer, software test, and program manager
- Acquired a general understanding of working in software engineering companies

Customer Service Sales Associate at HH Gregg Electronics

September 2013 - May 2014 (9 months)

- Gained experience in retail as a sales associate in the electronics/technology department for 4 months
- After 4 months, worked as a customer service merchandiser gaining experience in solving customer's technical issues

Computer Technician

January 2007 - May 2014 (7 years 5 months)

- Troubleshoot and repair computers.
- Build computers, install hardware, install software, and set up networks.

Teacher at Uplift, Inc. | Immersing Students in STEAM+CS Education

May 2013 - August 2013 (4 months)

- Developed course curriculum with my mentor at GMU
- Taught game design using App Inventor

Education

University of the District of Columbia

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science, 2017 - 2019

George Mason University

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science, 2013 - 2016

Hamza Hawkins

Software Engineer Intern at Microsoft



Contact Hamza on LinkedIn